7starsdirectory.com 2018-08-01

# Privacy Policy www.7StarsDirectory.com

## Who we are

Our website address is: http://www.7starsdirectory.com. and we are a web directory with business listings from all over the web. We help them getting a greater exposure and popularity on the internet.

## What personal data we collect and why we collect it

### Comments

When visitors leave comments on the site we collect the data shown in the comments form, and also the visitor’s IP address and browser user agent string to help spam detection.

### Media

If you upload images to the website, you should avoid uploading images with embedded location data (EXIF GPS) included. Visitors to the website can download and extract any location data from images on the website.

### Cookies

If you leave a comment on our site you may opt-in to saving your name, email address and website in cookies. These are for your convenience so that you do not have to fill in your details again when you leave another comment. These cookies will last for one year.

If you have an account and you log in to this site, we will set a temporary cookie to determine if your browser accepts cookies. This cookie contains no personal data and is discarded when you close your browser.

When you log in, we will also set up several cookies to save your login information and your screen display choices. Login cookies last for two days, and screen options cookies last for a year. If you select “Remember Me”, your login will persist for two weeks. If you log out of your account, the login cookies will be removed.

If you edit or publish an article/listing, an additional cookie will be saved in your browser. This cookie includes no personal data and simply indicates the post ID of the article you just edited. It expires after 1 day.

### Analytics

We use Google Analytics to collect anonymized data about visitors to this site. We use this data to improve visitor experience, and to help us make the site better and attract more visitors. Google Analytics records:

  * The website the visitor came from to get to this site.
  * The kind of computer they are using (Windows, Mac, etc. as well as information like screen resolution, web browser etc.)
  * The vistors general location (eg: London, United Kingdom)
  * Where the visitor clicked on the site and how long they stayed for.

You can prevent the collection of your data by Google Analytics by  [using a browser plugin to opt out of all Google Analytics tracking software](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout?hl=en).

In using Google Analytics, we are bound by the [Google Analytics Terms of Service](https://www.google.com/analytics/terms/us.html "Google Analytics Terms of Service")

### Site optimization and Security **  
**

We use [Cloudflare](https://www.cloudflare.com/ "Cloudflare") to help us optimize and protect this site. Cloudflare may place a cookie in your browser to provide its services. You can read more about this here – [Cloudflare Privacy & Security Policy](https://www.cloudflare.com/security-policy/ "Cloudflare Privacy & Security Policy")

### Financial Information

All our website financial transactions are handled through our GDPR compliant payment services provider [Paypal](https://www.paypal.com/ "Paypal"). Please review their respective Privacy Policies:

  * Paypal – <https://www.paypal.com/uk/webapps/mpp/ua/privacy-full>

We will share information with our payment service providers only to the extent necessary for the purposes of processing payments you make via our website and dealing with complaints and queries relating to such payments.

### Mailchimp

We use Mailchimp as our email marketing provider. Each new member is added in our Subscribers List using their email address and name. If you no longer wish to recieve our newsletter, you can click the Unsubscribe link form the bottom/footer of our emails and then system will delete you from our newsletter list. For more about Mailchimp Privacy Policy see the following link – [https://mailchimp.com/legal/privacy](https://mailchimp.com/legal/privacy/)

## How long we retain your data

If you leave a comment, the comment and its metadata are retained indefinitely. This is so we can recognize and approve any follow-up comments automatically instead of holding them in a moderation queue.

For users that register on our website (if any), we also store the personal information they provide in their user profile. All users can see, edit, or delete their personal information at any time (except they cannot change their username). Website administrators can also see and edit that information.

## What rights you have over your data

If you have an account on this site, or have left comments, you can request to receive an exported file of the personal data we hold about you, including any data you have provided to us. You can also request that we erase any personal data we hold about you. This does not include any data we are obliged to keep for administrative, legal, or security purposes.

## Where we send your data

Visitor comments may be checked through an automated spam detection service.

## Your contact information

www.7starsdirectory.com

contact@7starsdirectory.com
